https://github.com/nicktruby

hello! I am nick truby and this is me...

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicktruby



https://www.truby.io



In the midst of a career change, I recently completed a 12 week intensive software development course at _nology and I am now seeking to secure my first role as a junior software developer.

My motivation and desire to work in software development is driven by a genuine interest in the subject. I believe a career in this area will make the best use of my personal interests and natural talents as I enjoy problem solving and have a passion for being creative with visual design. These are key skills within software development and the area provides me with the opportunity to develop my abilities. It's really exciting and find it appealing that since IT is ever changing and updating, I'll have ample opportunity to always be learning new things.

A snapshot of my career background is as a successful team leader within John Lewis PLC where I daily practised empowered leadership, managing the customer journey & experience through visual merchandising, store design and operational management.



_nology

I made the commitment to this 12 week intensive software development course at _nology so I could develop my passion for tech. I am determined to take my genuine interest in the subject matter and turn it into a career and this programme provided a solid foundation of software development skills.

_nology taught me to code using modern techniques and frameworks from the start, guiding me so I'd avoid using incorrect or outdated practices. The curriculum gave me the structure to progressively build on my software development skills and capabilities.

Over a 5 week period I worked effectively within a team to complete the a real-world client project. We built a "Shift Reporter" web application for managing a mining workforce and fleet of vehicles. The team was made up of 8 developers and we used agile development and the Scrum framework, incorporating weekly sprints and pair-programming. I had the opportunity to start the project as team-leader, setting up the first sprint, running daily stand-ups, communicating with the clients/product owner and presenting our progress at the end of the week.

tech stack

- · ReactJS, Javascript ES6, SASS (SCSS), CSS3, HTML5
- Unit testing (Jest & Enzyme)
- Google Firebase (BaaS) Authorisation & Authentication, Firestore Document Database, Hosting
- Rest APIs using NodeJS & Express
- · Git & Github, Agile, Scrum, Pair programming

experience



NHS

<u>Trainee Software Developer</u> | _nology | (Sept 2020 to Dec 2020) see *left*

<u>Customer Service Advisor</u> | Sitel - NHS Test & Trace | May 2020 to present

Full remote work from home using AWS software. Customer advice line practicing empathy and professionalism whilst remaining calm and informative. Valuable time management experience as I balanced supporting my family with an income whilst investing full time education training at _nology.

<u>Operations & Visual Merchandising Manager</u> | John Lewis | Sept 2011 to May 2020

Deliver and influence brand image & customer experience through market leading store design, layout and presentation standards. Create the conditions for empowered individuals to thrive, coach and develop others (personal development, performance management, talent & succession planning). Lead and carry out the delivery of a safe, legal and compliant operation (H&S, Facilities, Logistics). Deliver commercial outcomes through driving sales and managing costs. Lead by example with outstanding internal and external customer service through manners and product knowledge. Develop a customer focused team, excelling in delivering exceptional customer service and shopkeeping. Chair the democratic function to unlock the potential for 120 Partners' opinion to shape and influence business performance. Manage multiple external stakeholders (Visual Merchandising, Logistics, Buying & Merchandising, Brands/Suppliers, Facilities).

<u>Deputy Store Manager</u> | Halfords (*Jul 2005 - Sept 2011*)

Deputise for store manager including sole site responsibility. Lead a sales team to drive profit through exemplary sales and service. Regionally train and develop across a network of store teams in safe and legal mechanical skills (Bike maintenance and repair, Child seat safety & fitting, Automobile

references

E/N: 81286376 https://www.johnlewispartnership.co.uk/meta/employee-reference.html
Robert Holder - Branch Manager JL Tamworth - holderrobert123@gmail.com
Neil Smith - Line Report JL Tamworth - hellesmith@outlook.com

about

I'm a passionate and driven individual. I like a challenge and, as a logical thinker, I enjoy solving problems. As a child I'd borrow a logic problems puzzle book my father took on holiday and I struggled to convince him at the time that I wasn't just looking the answers up in the back. As I've progressed through different roles in my career, I've found this key skill drives my success. I'm very competitive and I strive to be the best at whatever I put my mind too. I'm an ambitious person and aim to progress my career to a senior level. Throughout my employment I've demonstrated progression to management levels.

My development into leadership has taught me a wide array of soft skills and the effectiveness of a high performing team that supports and develops each other. I'm a team player that values the strengths of others and how to connect, calibrate and contribute together. Working in a democratic business. As an elected representative I've also learnt the ability to use team opinion to shape and influence business decision making and unlock the empowerment of individuals.

I'm adaptable, punctual and professional. I have a comprehensive understanding of effective communication and am skilled both verbally and in writing. I'm also a committed and loyal individual.

family

I am currently engaged to my lovely fiancé Sally, with our wedding organised for 2022. We were due to marry in 2021 but, like many couples, we decided to push it back a year with the uncertainty of Covid. We are very much looking forward to our special day and we both love to travel so bring on the honeymoon!

We have a son, Arthur, who is currently 18 months old. He is a joyous little boy, very inquisitive and like myself, enjoys puzzles. His confidence grows daily with his walking and he recently started going to Nursery too. Arthur is a large motivation in life for me. I want to be the best example for him and have a career I can be proud of and provide for my family. We enjoy spending time as a family going on days out and are members of the National Trust.

We live in Tamworth in the Midlands and we have family in Bristol, Swansea and Yeovil. Our family is close and we enjoy spending time together so often we congregate in Bristol as it is the epicentre of us all.

interests

Ever since my first mechanical experience working at Halfords, I have always enjoyed working with my hands. I still keep up bicycle mechanics as a hobby, but these days, as a family man, find my hands these days are more commonly used on DIY projects. Most recently I took on the challenge of refitting our bathroom.

I've always had an interest in tech. I bought my first Mac in 2005 and have been committed to the brand since. It was this purchase that started my enjoyment with computer media. For example, in the effort to learn I did a bit of professional video editing. I've taken apart and serviced many personal electronics in the past as I enjoy understanding how things are made.

When I'm not spending time with my family or working I do like video gaming. I'm a console gamer and have recently made the switch to next generation with the PS5. I'm a completionism and enjoy trophy hunting on single player RPG games, and play online mostly on Call of Duty zombies and battle royale.

I also enjoy TV and Cinema, and anything Star Wars related.

education

2009-2010 | NVQ Level 2 Traineeship - Customer Service

2008-2009 | NVQ Level 2 Traineeship - Mechanical Engineering (Cytech -Cycle Mechanic)

Apple Certified Professional |
New Technology Institute
(City of Birmingham University)
16/01/2008 |
FCP101 | Final Cut Pro 6 : Level 1
04/06/2008 |
FCP300 | Final Cut Pro 6 : Level 2
12/11/2008 |
MOT101 | Motion 3 : Level 1
15/10/2008 |
COL101 | Color : Level 1
03/04/2009 |
DVDSP101 | DVD Studio Pro : Level 1
15/05/2009 |
STP101 | Soundtrack Pro 2 : Level 1

2004-2006 | 6th Form (A-Levels) | Mathematics, I.C.T (Information Communication Technology), Theatre Studies

1999-2004 | Wilnecote High School (GCSE's), Maths, Science, I.C.T, Geography, English, French, Drama.